字幕来源：射手网
后期：YHBaekdolu
假日客栈
Happy Holiday
十二月二十四日圣诞夜
圣诞快乐  巴德
Merry Christmas, Bud.
谢谢也祝你圣诞快乐
Thank you. Merry Christmas to you.
好了  嗨  组长
Okay. Hi, chief.
今夜演出  翰欧文  哈弟与狄森
进来
Come in.
哈罗  甜心
Hello, honey.
今晚是在娱乐界的最后一夜
Well, this is our last night in show business.
很多感触吧
Some feeling, huh?
感触很深
Some feeling.
婚姻执照和戒指准备好了
I got the ring and the license.
甜心我们准备好了
Honey, we're ready.
衣服上面应有个钩子吧
Say, there's a hook leftover at the top here.
不是吗
Should that be?
没关系啦
Never mind that, dear.
我来弄吧
I'll take care of it.
-吉姆  -什么
-Jim. -Huh?
我觉得领带很难看呢
Well, I think that tie is terrible.
又怎样  明天我就是农夫了
Who cares? Tomorrow I'm a farmer.
最好换一条吧
You'd better go change it.
甜心
Honey,
当你摇动着脚趾
when you flip them those twinkle toes,
谁会注意到我的领带呢
who's gonna be looking at my tie?
还有五分钟快点吧
You only have five minutes. Hurry.
好  我去换
Okay, I'm on my way.
-他怎么说  -我没告诉他
-What'd he say? -I didn't tell him.
为何不  我们彼此相爱
Why not? We love each other.
你想继续跳舞
You want to continue dancing.
我知道但是他很无辜呢
I know, but...he gets a look.
他看来就是那个样子
Oh, he's always had that look.
这跟感情无关
It doesn't mean anything emotionally.
他的脾气太大了
It has to do with his liver.
跟他说他搞错了
Tell him you've made a mistake.
你不想放弃个人事业
You don't want to give up your career
住到乡下农场
and live on a farm.
但他已经买了农场
But he's already bought the farm
还有戒指和证书呢
and the license and the ring.
我无法开口
Oh, I can't tell him.
好吧我来说  等表演完就说
All right. I will. Right after our number.
听我说亲爱的  别软弱
Listen, darling, don't weaken.
想着我们一起生活
Think of our life together.
想着钻石  皮草
Think of diamonds, of sables,
还有单独阁楼呢
of your own little penthouse.
这是你的承诺
Is that a promise?
想想未来
Well, just think about them
美好的时光吧
for the time being.
-上场了狄森小姐  -谢谢你
-Ready, Miss Dixon. -Oh, thank you.
跟本扣不上呢
This thing didn't come out even.
我来弄吧
Oh, I'll fix it.
-要迟到了  -我爱你
-We have to hurry. -I love you.
我爱你和吉姆
I love you... and Jim.
当然我也爱吉姆
I love Jim too. But after all,
我是说跟你的亲密不同啦
I mean, let's not be too chummy.
她来了  街上走过来
Here she comes Down the street
老天啊  真可爱呢
My, oh, my Ain't she sweet
过来的人  是我的最爱
Why, here comes my hot toddy
为她死都愿意
Over my dead body
我会唱歌博取她芳心
I'll capture her heart singing
看我跳只舞
Just wait until she gets
就改变了
a load of my dancing
当我开口高歌后
Just wait till I start singing
我会带着她
I'll take her
一路跳舞下去
strolling down the road with my dancing
唱首情歌准没错
I can't go wrong A tender song
她会发现我迷人之处
And she'll discover my charms
迷人的舞步令她跌倒
Some fancy taps and she'll collapse
倾倒在我的怀里
And fall right into my arms
我高歌会博得她芳心
I'll capture her heart singing
不会  你没有机会了
Oh, no. You haven't a chance
只要我开始跳舞
When I go into my dance
我一辈子为你唱情歌
I'll take you through life singing
啦啦啦的
La-da-da-Di, la-da-da-Di La-da-da-Di
蹦蹦蹦
Boom boom Boo-boo-boo-boo-boo-boom
你要当我的新娘舞伴
I'll make you my wife dancing
如果除了唱歌还能跳舞
If you could dance instead of sing
我就会试着爱上你
I'd learn to love you somehow
如果除了跳舞还能唱歌
If you could sing instead of dance
现在就可以娶我回去
I'd take you home with me now
蹦蹦蹦
Boom boo-boo-boo-boom Boo-boo-boo-boo-boom
你的歌声没有感情
The way you sing don't mean a thing
你最好努力学跳舞
You'd better stick to you dance
而你跳舞没什么帮助
And as for you Your dance won't do
你需要唱出罗曼史
You'll have to sing for romance
-我会得到她芳心  -我会赢得她芳心
-I'll capture her heart -I'll capture her heart
-唱歌  -跳舞
-Singing -Dancing
圣诞礼物不太吸引你  是吗
Not much of a Christmas present for you, is it?
我是说  我们两人  都针对着你
I mean, both of us walking out on you.
别担心我  小鬼  我会做的很好
Don't worry about me, kid. I'll do all right.
真是个笨蛋
What a chump.
你看不出来我们在争什么吗
Can't you see what we're walking out on?
碾米呢  一年365天
The grind, 365 days a year.
你上次什么时候休假
When was the last time you had a day off?
我不知道也许是去年吧
I don't know. Maybe last year.
你听说过感恩节
Did you ever hear of Thanksgiving
劳动节和独立日吗
or Labor Day or the Fourth of July?
-好像有  -你知道是什么意思吧
-Vaguely. -You know what they are, don't you?
是假期  休息日  有很多种假期
They're holidays, days of rest. There's lots of them.
所以日历上日期是红字
They mark them in red on the calendar
你不会错过他们的
so you can't miss them.
当假期来到时
What happens in show business
表演将会怎样
when a holiday comes along?
会有特别节目
You give an extra performance.
兄弟  我不干
Not for me, brother.
丽拉和我要去
Lila and I are going up to
康乃迪克州的农场
that farm in Connecticut.
我们按照日历假期度假
We're gonna live by the calendar.
-吉姆  -什么
-Say, Jim. -Hmm?
有件事情要让你知道
Uh, there's something you should know.
我知道  泰德
Oh, I know, Ted.
我跟你的感觉一样
I feel the same way about you.
你知道  我们追求同样的目标
You know, we've had our ups and our downs.
为了女人有些小争执  但是
We've fought a little over women, but...
我知道  但是
I know, but...
抱歉  吉米  这就是人生啊
Sorry, Jimmy boy, but that's life.
我敢跟你打包票
If I'm not the best manager in the business,
我是秀场最佳的经纪人
I'll eat a mechanic's shirt.
在俱乐部十五个星期
Fifteen weeks at the Park Club,
你和丽拉名利双收
sight unseen, for you and Lila.
每周两百美元
Two hundred dollars a week more than you were
比你在农场干活强多了
getting with the farmer thrown in.
-怎么了  -我没告诉他呢
-What's the matter? -I haven't told him.
还没告诉他吗
You haven't told him?
你还没跟他说
没告诉我什么  什么
Haven't told me what? What?
那是什么  什么事情
What is it? What's the news?
别生气  吉姆答令
Well, don't be upset, Jim dear.
我还是一样爱你啊
It isn't that I don't love you.
我爱  你们两人我都爱
I do. I love everybody.
当泰德解释他有多爱我
But when Ted explained how much
而且
he loved me and...
在霎那间我们发现
All at once we both realized that
彼此真的相爱
we belonged together.
我们两人将我们的爱
The two of us, dedicating our lives
用双脚让大家得到欢乐
to making people happy with our feet.
你们两人吗
The two of you, huh?
分享你们的爱
Dedicating your lives
用双脚带给大家欢乐
to making people happy with your feet.
真甜密  刚才我表现的踢腿
That's sweet. Well, I guess that kick
应该是好的开始吧
I just got was a good start, huh?
抱歉吉姆  人生就是如此
Sorry, Jimmy boy, but that's life.
我们现在找到了幸福  吉姆
It's best you found out now, Jim.
你不会让丽拉不快乐吧
You wouldn't want to make Lila unhappy.
不  不  我想让丽拉很快乐
Oh, no, no, i wouldn't want to make Lila unhappy.
不要现在  现在我真的了解她
Not now, now that I really know her.
这是什么吱吱声音
What a narrow squeak that was.
你说这话什么意思
What do you mean by that?
没什么亲爱的  你快乐我也就快乐
Oh, nothing, honey. I'm happy you're happy.
你这么说好像是
That little speech sounds like
钱很好赚呢
the crackle of Confederate money.
小鬼
Well, kids,
我还是要跟你竞争
I'm still going to rejoin the human race.
希望你的假期表演
I hope you get a lot of work, holidays included.
能够多加一些
Dance yourselves into
舞蹈在里面
beautiful nervous breakdowns.
如果你想要看我表演
If you ever want to look me up,
可以找的到我的
you know where to find me.
密德谷  康乃迪克州
Midville, Connecticut,
我在大树阴下休息呢
under a large shady tree, just being lazy.
休息
Lazy
我想要休息
I want to be lazy
我要整天待在阳光下
I long to be out in the sun
什么事也不用做
With no work to be done
就在凉亭下
Under that awning
人们说太阳下
They call the sky
令人骚痒和懒散
Stretching and yawning
抛开所有的世俗
And let the world go drifting by
我要深入的观察
I want to peek through the deep
野外的树木数着羊只
Tangled wild woods counting sheep
直到婴儿般的鼾睡
till I sleep like a child would
有大堆的书籍
With a great big valise full
在宁静的环境中阅读
of books to read where it's peaceful
我在打发时间
While I'm killing time
感恩节
圣诞夜
密德谷  康乃迪克州
泰德・汉诺瓦
俱乐部  纽约州
今晚见圣诞快乐  吉姆
在疗养院休息时
So Lazy Acres was
有了好点子
a snare and a delusion, huh?
兄弟  这里有
Oh, brother! There's the
全世界最苦的工作
hardest work in the world.
也许在城里会比较快乐  吉姆
Maybe you'd be happier back in town, Jim.
当然  如果你能
Of course, if you get
从事农耕
that agricultural urge again,
你就会养天竺鼠了
you can raise a geranium.
不  你听我说
Oh, no. Wait till you hear.
这是我人生中
I think I've dreamed up
最大的梦想
the greatest idea I ever had.
你还有好种子呢
And you've had some pips.
这次不可能失败
Oh, but this can't miss.
我将农场改成酒店
I'm turning the farm into an inn!
什么样的酒店
But what an inn.
兄弟你看看这个
Here, read up, brother.
假日酒店  密德谷  康乃迪克州
"Holiday Inn. Midville, Connecticut.
远离高速公路在农场休闲
Get off the highway and relax on a farm.
跳舞  娱乐  家常菜
Dancing, entertainment, home cooking.
只有假日开放
Open holidays only."
Open holidays only?
大概有多少天啊
How many of those are there?
大约有十五天
Oh, there's about 15.
我一年三百五十天
That gives me 350 days a year
都待在那里了
to kick around in.
你可以这么说
You would think of that.
你想在这种
Did you get your discharge
疗养院赚钱
from that sanitarium?
你不用担心
Oh, don't you worry.
我会成功的
This is going to work.
每天都有歌手演唱
I'm having auditions every day.
如果你有影响力
If you run into any talent,
怎么请这些人呢
will you send them out?
当然等我回来就办
Sure, as soon as I get back.
今晚我要飞到迈阿密海滩
I'm flying down to Miami Beach tonight...
跟泰德和丽拉签约  丽拉
setting an engagement with Ted and Lila
你忘了带花
You forgot the flowers.
别太兴奋
I don't get excited.
机场有花店
There's a flower shop out at the airport.
我答应送给她
I guarantee to have orchids
兰花呢
before her first number.
小鬼  父亲节的礼物
Boy, you'd better.
也一起
Cause I remember this kid
送吧
even expects presents on Father's Day.
祝好运了吉姆  再见泰德
Well, good luck, Jim. So long, Ted.
我祝你旅途平安  多谢了  没问题
Have a nice trip. I mean, yeah, thanks, I will.
这提醒了我  我忘了给他
That reminds me, I forgot to give him...
一个小小
a little Christmas remembrance
圣诞节回忆
I brought along.
送给你们每个人的
Got one here for each of you.
真的很贴心呢  是什么啊
Say, this is swell. What is it?
手工制的桃子酱
Homemade peach preserves.
在我到疗养院时
I put them up myself before
自己做的呢
I went into the sanitarium.
我可以试试看吗
Boy, do I go for those!
好啊它可用于
Why, they're great on...on,
用在农场上呢
uh...Or even plain.
吃了不会发胖呢
They're nonfattening too.
回农场的这趟旅途很遥远
Well, it's a long trip back to the farm.
我想该走了
I think I'll get along.
替我跟丽拉打招呼
Will you say hello to Lila for me?
你要赶上表演呢
You've got to catch the act.
我们有新的内容
We've got some new routines.
等表演结束后
And then after the show...
我不喜欢这间夜总会的气芬
I don't think they like this nightclub air.
等等我想你该等丽拉的爆炸
Wait. You'd better wait for Lila's.
我想丹尼的最大声
I think Danny's was the loudest.
是不同的音调
It was a different tone.
降低音吗
Dawn patrol, huh?
哈罗  我来迟了吗
Halo. Am I too late?
你来的正是时候
You would've been in another minute.
丹尼・瑞德
Danny Reed.
听着  我必需等那个人
Listen, I have to wait on that man.
-但是呢  -我每天晚上都有空
-But, uh... -I'll work five nights free.
最好什么事
Anything. Just leave me alone
都别来烦我
and don't butt in.
你想要什么
What would you like?
兰花你们有最好的
Orchids. The finest you've got.
-胸花吗  -不要一束花
-Corsage? -No, no, a dozen.
盛开的看来不要太密集
Loose, looking like they don't care.
-好的  -写着"丽拉爱你的泰德"
-All right. -There. "Lila... love, Ted."
请于晚间十一点前送到俱乐部
Have them delivered to Miss Lila Dixon
给一位丽拉・狄森小姐
at the Club Pierre before 11:00 tonight.
很抱歉  我们的送货车
Oh, I'm sorry, but our delivery truck
目前在跑最后一趟
is on its last trip...
十一点前不会回来的
and won't be back until after 11:00.
派个小弟送去吧
How about a messenger boy?
在圣诞夜的深夜
It's impossible to guarantee
实在不敢保证呢
delivery this late on Christmas Eve.
为了帮你忙我亲自送到
But to help you out, I'll take them.
拿去吧
Oh, there you are.
一打的兰花拜托了
A dozen orchids, please.
小姐你是救世主
Lady, you're a lifesaver.
拿去这五美金
Here. Here's $5.00.
带你男朋友
Take your boyfriend out
出去好好玩一下
and show him a good time.
就当做是私人恩惠吧
Let's consider this a personal favor.
我不能跟陌生人
Well, I can't leave town
出城呢
indebted to a stranger.
想看看今晚
Would you like to see the floor show
俱乐部里的秀吗
at the Club tonight?
我很想啊  但是
I'd like to very much, but...
行  你只要把
All right, now you just give
名片交给法兰科
this card to Francois,
他会给你
and he'll seat you
找个好位子的
at the entertainer's table.
你就是瑞德先生啊
Why, you're Mr. Reed!
-不好  -我是琳达・梅生
-Uh...oh. -I'm Linda Mason.
我在这里兼差
This is a part-time job.
事实上我会唱歌跳舞
Actually, I sing and dance.
-瑞德先生  我想  -我知道你有在学习
-Mr. Reed, I want... -I know, I know.
从婴儿时期
You've studied dancing
就开跳舞了
since you were a child.
你在每间百老汇经纪公司
You spent long, weary hours
耗了很长的时间
in every agency on Broadway.
但现在我要
But just now I happen
赶搭飞机去迈阿密
to be catching a plane to Mi...
当然  只要你跟我说我不行
Of course, once you told me I was no good,
我就会死了这条心  找份正常工作
I could get a job in a bargain basement and like it.
听我说  坦白讲  只要我能够
Now look, honestly, as soon as I get...
当然啦  你很努力
Oh, of course, sure. You worked hard.
想要有个机会又怎样呢
You want a chance. So what?
我会给你个机会
So I'm going to give it to you.
-一份工作  -是的
-A job? -Er huh...
在康乃迪克
A friend of mine is opening
我有个朋友开了个酒店
a place in Connecticut:
假日酒店
Holiday Inn.
明天你拿我的名片去找他
You take that card out there tomorrow,
就说我推鉴的  一切就搞定了
tell him I sent you and you'll be all set.
瑞德先生  我要
Mr. Reed, how could I
-怎样谢你呢  -不必
-possibly thank you? -Don't.
只要帮我把花送到
Just deliver those orchids
让我赶上飞机吧
and let me catch my plane.
这桌预留给乐队了抱歉
This table's reserved for the band. Excuse me!
真热闹呢  对吗
Fussy, isn't he?
给我来杯咖啡吧
I think I'll have a bowl of coffee, huh?
-小姐呢  -咖啡
-And the lady? -Coffee.
我们好像这里最穷的人
We seem to be on the 40-cent tour here.
真糗呢
It is embarrassing.
-我是吉姆哈第  -我是琳达・梅生
-I'm Jim Hardy. -Linda Mason.
秀场里有朋友吗
Got a friend in the show?
瑞德先生邀请我来的
Well, I'm here at Mr. Reed's invitation.
丹尼啊  你认识泰德・汉诺瓦
Oh, Danny. Then you know Ted Hanover?
当然啊
What, yes, naturally.
老天他对女士真的很有礼呢
Oh, my. He's quite a man with the ladies, that Ted.
说实话  他很有吸引力呢
Well, after all, he's a very attractive man.
-你认识他  -是的
-Do you know him? -Oh, yes, yes.
事实上我正考虑
As a matter of fact, I've been considering
泰德和他伙伴  加入我新的俱乐部
Ted and his partner for my new club.
-你有场地吗  -是的
-Oh, you have a place? -Oh, yes, yes.
我不知道他的表演
I don't know though. His act
对我的大场地是否合适
might not go so well in a place as large as mine.
我觉得场地
Well, I've found that the size
并非重要因素
of a place doesn't matter...
最重要的还是演员的特色
if one has sufficient personality.
你有这种体认  你也在秀场表演
That's what you've found, huh? You in show business?
我是琳达・梅生
Oh... I'm Linda Mason.
琳达・梅生
Oh, Linda Mason!
我能整夜跳舞
I could dance nightly
紧紧的拥着你  我的甜心
Just holding you tightly my sweet
我能够持续
I could keep right on
因为你的脚步如此轻盈
Because you're so light on your feet
你是最佳舞伴
You're easy to dance with
毫无疑问的
There is no doubt
我们在人群中站立
In the way we stand out in a crowd
虽然跳舞在进行
Though it's called dancing
对我来说是罗曼史
To me it's romancing out loud
你是最佳舞伴
You're easy to dance with
我会一直爱着你
Loving you the way I do
让你成为最佳舞伴
Makes you easy to dance with
所以我都能抓的住节拍
That is why I'm always right on the beat
在男人臂膀里的时光
All those times in one man's arms
让你成为最佳舞伴
Make you easy to dance with
我的思绪无法控制舞步
I can hardly keep my mind on my feet
我们永远跳下去
Let's dame forever
快点说永远也不要停
Come on say we'll never be through
你是最佳舞伴
It's so easy to dance with you
你真的是个好舞伴
You're easy to dance with
你真的是个  好舞伴
It's so easy to dance with you
跟你共舞真容易
It's so easy to dance
跟你共舞  真容易
It's so easy to dance with you
-太棒了  -表演很棒吧是吗
-That was wonderful. -It's a great act, isn't it?
他们来了
Here they come.
-谁  -泰德和丽拉
-Who? -Ted and Lila.
怎么啦
Hey, what's the matter?
-哈罗  丽拉你好吗  -吉米小子
-Hello, Lila. How are you? -Jimmy boy!
-真高兴看见你  -看见你真好
-I'm so glad to see you. -It's good to see you.
我以为你一个人呢
I thought you were alone, Jim.
你朋友是谁  她在急什么啊
Who's your friend and what's her hurry?
别问我  她是你的朋友呢
Don't ask me. She's your friend.
-我的  -是的
-Mine? -Yeah.
她在怕什么面对我吗
What is she afraid of, facing me?
答令  我发誓绝没有
Darling, I swear I never...
-"答令  我发誓"  你说谎  -该你了
-'Daring, I swear.' You lie. -You're on.
-如果你没有  -谢个幕吧
-If you don't... -Take a bow.
-安可
-Encore!
这就是假日酒店
So this is Holiday Inn.
是的  开幕后就是了
-Yeah, will be if it ever opens up.
为何还不开张营业
Why shouldn't it open?
我不该这么说但用一桶苹果
I ain't one to talk, but you could buy...
的价格就可买下一半股份
a half interest in this place for a barrel of apples.
下班车到纽约  七点四十三分
Next train for New York's at 7:43
如果挥手她就停下
if we can flag her down.
我来找工作的  老板在哪
Say, I'm looking for a job. Where's the boss?
在这里  我马上就下来
Right here. I'll be down in a second.
你就是不确定汉诺瓦和迪森
So you're the big shot that didn't know whether...
是否适合这里的大人物罗
Hanover and Dixon were good enough for your place.
不尽然  你看来也很像呢
That wasn't exactly hay you were throwing, either.
"我是琳达・梅生"
'I'm Linda Mason.'
-圣诞快乐  -圣诞快乐
-Merry Christmas. -Merry Christmas.
好吧  你是冒牌我是虚假
All right, you're a fake and I'm a phony.
我们都湿了
And we're both soaked.
-你受伤了吗  -待会再检查
-Are you hurt? -I'll check later.
走吧  我们离开这里
Come on, let's get out of this
-以免感冒着凉  -好的
-before you catch cold. -All right. Oh!
就是这里了
Well, here's what cooks.
这里真的很美呢
Why, this is darling.
它真的像农场这么大吗
Was it as large as this when it was a farmhouse?
是的  原屋主逃离纽约
Yeah, it was built by a fellow
在这里盖的
who felt cramped in New York.
他要远离木材吧
He ran out of lumber, though.
-妈咪  -来了
-Oh, Mamie! -Coming
-你们名字叫妈咪  -不是
-Is your names Mamie? -No.
进到厨房里
Get back in the kitchen.
-老天怎么回事啊  -有点小意外啦
-My, my, what's happened? -Oh, we had a little accident.
妈咪  这位是琳达・梅生
Mamie, this is Miss Linda Mason.
你好吗
How do you do?
很高兴认识你琳达小姐
Pleased to know you, Miss Linda.
这些是她的孩子
And these are her children.
这是达芬  还有范德堡
There's Daphne and there's Vanderbilt.
你好吗
How do you do?
妈咪  你带梅生小姐到客房
Mamie, will you take Miss Mason up to the guest room...
提供她需要的一切物品
and change her into anything that'll fit her well?
我们得弄干衣服
We get to cloth dryer.
好的吉米先生  走吧  亲爱的
Sure thing, Mr. Jimmy. Come on, honey.
我到客厅去
I'll see about getting
点壁炉生个火吧
a fire ready in the living room.
琳达是你的名字
Is your names Miss Linda?
-不是  -不是
-No. -No.
我不知道  听起来好像
I don't know. It sounds like
对夜晚很崇景呢
something you'd dream about at night.
会很美的
It would be wonderful.
你醒来后会发觉它是没用的
Then you'd wake up and realize it couldn't work.
会有用的  如果
Oh, it'll work if
我将点子提供给表演者
I can sell the idea to some performers.
他们会考虑利润分享
They seem to think that profit sharing means
使空肚子里面装满食物
taking bows on an empty stomach.
所以你今晚才不开幕
So that's why you're not open tonight.
我还想将独特的才华
Well, I'm also particular about
加以发挥
the kind of talent I'm going to use.
-一年有十五天的假期呢  -对
-Fifteen holidays a year. -Mm-hmm.
-你是个懒骨头  -不  看情况而定
-You're a lazy fellow. -No, not especially.
只是有自己的生活方式
Just have my own ideas about living.
我老爸很像你  只是个一家之主
My father was like you. Just a man with a family.
没有太多的要求  无所适事
Never  amounted  to  much,  didn’t  care.
但只要他活着
But as long as he was alive,
我们大家都衣食无虞
we always had plenty to eat and clothes to keep us warm.
-你很快乐吗  -是的
-Were you happy? -Yes.
那他就是个成功的老爸
Then your father was a very successful man.
希望我也能如此
Hope I can do as well.
我来这谋求工作  你会雇用我吗
I came out here for a job. Could you use me?
看有没适合你的角色  你会什么
I might find a spot for you my first show. What can you do?
我懂得一点唱歌跳舞
Oh, I sing a little and dance.
刚开始薪水可能不太高
Couldn't guarantee any salary at first.
现在我们采用拆帐制度
Right now I've got the ledger in an iron lung.
我对薪水多少不计较
I don't care if you pay off in eggs.
-只要有机会就好  -看看你能做什么吧
-Just give me a chance. -Let's see what you can do.
谢谢  多谢了
Thanks...Thanks a lot.
我为每个假期都写了主题音乐
I've written special music for each holiday.
这对我自己的承诺
This gives me a chance to
有个实现的机会
keep a little promise I made to myself.
我希望今晚能唱这首歌曲
I said I was going to sing this song at the Inn tonight.
我梦想着
I'm dreaming
一个白色的圣诞
Of a white Christmas
跟我所熟悉的
Just like the ones
完全一样
I used to know
树梢发出光辉
Where the treetops glisten
孩子在聆听
And children listen
听着
To hear
雪地里的铃声
Sleigh bells in the snow
我梦想着
I'm dreaming
一个白色的圣诞
Of a white Christmas
还有写着每封
With every Christmas card
圣诞卡
I write
希望你的日子
May your days
都快乐充满希望
Be merry and bright
祝福你们大家
And may all your
圣诞节
Christmases
充满白色
Be white
我梦想着
I'm dreaming
一个白色的圣诞节
Of a white Christmas
如果过去熟悉的一般
Just like the ones I used to know
树梢发出了光辉
Where the treetops glisten.
Where the treetops glisten
-孩子在聆听  -孩子在聆听
-And children listen. -And children listen
-仔细听  -仔细听
-To hear -To hear
雪地里的铃声
Sleigh bells in the snow
我梦想着
I'm dreaming
一个白色的圣诞
Of a white Christmas
我写下
With every Christmas card
每张圣诞卡
I write
祝福你每天快乐
May your days be merry
充满希望
And bright
祝福所有人的
And may all
圣诞节
Your Christmases
充满白色
Be white
十二月三十一号
去哪里
新年快乐
Happy holidays
希望之钟不断的敲着
While the merry bells keep ringing
每个愿望都能实现
May your every wish come true
新年快乐
Happy holidays
希望日历不断带来
May the calendar keep bringing
快乐的假期给你
Happy holidays to you
如果你不断受烦脑所苦
If you're burdened down with trouble
如果你神经衰弱
If your nerves are wearing thin
把车子停在路边
Park your load down the road
进来光临假日酒店
And come to Holiday Inn
如果交通让你烦心
If the traffic noise affects you
就像吱吱叫的小提琴
Like a squeaky violin
把你的烦恼丢在楼下
Kick your cares down the stairs
进来光临假日酒店
And come to Holiday Inn
如果找不到关心的人
If you can't find somebody who
让你心灵暂得舒解
Will set your heart awhirl
坐上汽车或机车
Get in your car and motor to
来到男女相会之地
The home of Boy Meets Girl
如果你太照固自己
If you're laid up with a breakdown
抛弃所有的维他命
Throw away your vitamin
-找护士  -只会变更糟
-Don't get worse -Grab your nurse
来到假日酒店
And come to Holiday Inn
新年快乐
Happy holidays
希望日历不断带来
May the calendar keep bringing
快乐的日子给你
Happy holidays to you
新年快乐  泰德
Happy New Year, Ted.
纽约12月31日  泰德・汉诺瓦
皮耶俱乐部纽约州
抱歉答令今晚飞到德州
嫁给世上的百万富翁
希望你找的新搭档
爱你的  丽拉
不好
No!
法兰科你看见汉诺瓦先生吗
Francois, have you seen Mr. Hanover?
两次呢先生
Twice, sir.
-怎么回事  -头一次呢先生
-What happened? -The first time, sir,
他从房间出来手上拿着封电报
he came from his room with a telegram in his hand.
他点了威士忌和苏打各一瓶
He ordered Scotch and soda, a bottle of each.
我知道  我知道了  然后呢
I know. I know. What then?
第二次他问到康乃迪克怎么走
The second time, he asked which way is Connect-i-cut.
-康乃迪克  -康乃迪克
-Connecticut. -Connecticut.
他说那里有个朋友  也知道女孩的事呢
He said he has a friend there who knows about women too.
为何你不阻止他
Why didn't you stop him?
我怎能阻止他呢先生
How could I stop him, sir,
我不知道康乃迪克怎么走
when I don't know which way is Connecticut?
谁说假日酒店没有用
Who said Holiday Inn wouldn't work?
今晚就会大赚一笔了哈
We're gonna divvy up a stack of money tonight, huh?
老天啊
Man, man!
我这有个小姑娘
I've got a landlady who's gonna
想跟你索取签名照呢
ask for your autographed picture.
每个人都有吗
Everybody get something?
好了  行了  要睡觉了  已经很晚了
All right. Come on now. Go to bed now. It's getting late.
晚安
Good right.
-晚安  -晚安
-Good night. -Good night.
看时间要到了
Look, it's almost time.
它会直接跳上去对吧
It's practically straight up, isn't it?
还一分钟就半夜
One minute to midnight
还剩一分钟
One minute to go
一分钟道再见
One minute to say good-bye
在说哈罗以前
Before we say hello
让新年就从今夜
Let's start the New Year right
十二点开始吧
Twelve o'clock tonight
当他们关上灯光
When they dim the light
让我们开始
Let's begin
跟旧的一年吻别
Kissing the old year out
亲吻新年的到来
Kissing the New Year in
一齐注视旧的一年逝去
Let's watch the old year die
跟它说声再见
With a fond good-bye
我们的希望高涨
And our hopes as high
像个风筝般
As a kite
我们的爱不会有错
How can our love go wrong
如果迎接好的新年开始
If we start the New Year right
到了现在是午夜了  我们在一楼见吧
That's it, that's midnight. I'll see you out on the floor.
好的
All right.
大家一起来吧  新年快乐
Come on, everybody! Happy New Year!
寻找你的舞伴跳舞吧
Get your partner and dance.
新年快乐
Happy holiday.
Happy New Year.
-我忘了支票了  -你不需要的
-I forgot my check. -You won't need that,
但需要穿件夹克呢
but you'll need your coat.
-新年快乐  -新年快乐
-Happy New Year. -Happy New Year.
你也一样  你们都是  我要
Same to you. Many of them. I gotta...
快点啦吉姆  你要跳个舞啊
Come on, Jim, you gotta dance.
你要跟我一起跳  快啊你一定要跳舞啊
Oh, you gotta dance with me. Come on, you gotta dance.
不  我不能啊
No, I can't. Oh!
-汉诺瓦先生  -他是泰德・汉诺瓦呢
-Why, Mr. Hanover! -That's Ted Hanover.
-等等我要走了  -我不需要泰德・汉诺瓦
-Wait a minute. I gotta go. -I don't want Ted Hanover.
-我要你  现在是新年了  -我知道
-I want you. This is New Year's, -I know.
小鬼
kid.
泰德
Ted
-他没有醉只是昏了  -怎么了
-He wasn't drunk. It's a gag. -What happened?
泰德・汉诺瓦和他的新搭档
Ted Hanover with his new partner.
他们很棒呢
They were great!
新搭档
New partner?
-你最好回去吧  -我很抱歉
-You'd better get back. -I'm sorry.
如果我知道他会这样
If I'd known how he was...
他没事的啦  一个礼拜吧
Oh, he'll be all right
泰德会醒的  你最好快一点
in a week or ten days. You'd better hurry.
泰德  泰德
Ted! Ted!
泰德  他怎样了
Ted! Oh. How is he?
他着凉了
He's out cold.
发烧还是发冷  把跳舞鞋放在我办公室
Hot or cold, he can keep his dancing shoes in my office.
你听到那些掌声吗  是的  很不错呢
-Did you hear that applause? -Yeah, it went pretty good.
我担心是他失去了丽拉
And I was worried about his losing Lila.
失去了丽拉
Losing Lila?
是的  她今晚私奔了
Yeah, she eloped tonight
跟德州来的德州佬
with some Texan from Texas...
手上还戴着  泰德送的订婚戒指呢
with Ted's engagement ring on her finger.
管他的  跑了一个马子
But who cares? You lose one girl,
再找一个嘛  人生嘛
you find another. That's life.
很好是吗  又开始啦
-That's good, huh? -Here we go again.
进来
Come in! Oh.
早安泰德  早啊
-Good morning, Ted. -Good morning, Ooh.
头还痛吗  我在哪里啊
-Got a little head? -Say, where am I?
你在假日酒店呢  我怎会来到这里
-You're in Holiday Inn. -How'd I get here?
谁带我来的
Who brought me?
我想你是在诊所  被一辆吉普车送来的
You were clinging to the undercarriage of a jeep, I think.
拿去慢慢的喝吧
Here, have a slug out of the mug.
你是说什么都不记得吗
You mean, you don't remember anything?
想想看我接到丽拉一通电报
let's see, I had a wire from Lila...
告诉我她要结婚了
telling me she was gonna marry
嫁给百万富翁还是什么的
some millionaire or something.
是的  这些我都还记得
-Yeah. -I remember that all right.
然后我喝了杯酒
Uh, then I had a drink.
一杯酒  老天你喝的烂醉
A drink? Boy, you were fractured.
然后  我决定
And then, uh, I decided
必需跟老友吉姆谈谈
I had to talk to my old pal Jim.
别的都不记得了吗
You don't remember anything else?
就是这么多了
No, that's all.
除了我从这里出去后
Except that I must have been killed
被杀死或是别的事
on the way out here or something.
你真的一片空白啊  丽拉真的太可惜了
You really come up empty, huh? Too bad about Lila.
我想你最好别单独承受
I think you're better off doing a single.
你天生就是个独行侠  呢
You're a born soloist.
不  不  吉姆  我需要
Oh, no, no, Jim. I've got
有个搭档  等我找到的时候
to have a partner. And when I find her...
是啊  我知道  你会跟她陷入情网
Yeah, I know, you'll fall in love with her.
-新年快乐  -不要这样
-Happy New Year! -Oh, don't do that.
为何你不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
让我担心他失去了丽拉
Letting me worry about his losing Lila,
还有他一直叮这女孩这么紧
and all the time he's got this girl on the leash.
-什么女孩  -老天  你一定很兴奋吧
-What girl? -Boy, you must've been high.
跟你的新女搭档
Doing a complete dance routine
跳完了所有的舞而你
with your new partner and you...
你不知道她是谁
You don't know who she is?
我跟新搭档跳舞  何时  哪里
I danced with a new partner? When? Where?
在这里  昨晚啊  想想吧泰德
Here! Last night! Think, Ted.
记得吗
Remember?
等等  我记得了
Wait a minute. I remember.
我到这里将近午夜
I got here just about midnight.
有个女孩子
There was a girl.
我们共舞
We danced.
她长的什么样子
What'd she look like?
我不知道
Oh... I don't know.
我只看到模糊的轮廓
All I saw was a vague outline.
她的一切你都不记得吗
Can't you remember anything about her?
嗯  我只记得跟她跳舞
Well, I remember dancing with her.
如果能再次跟她共舞
If I ever dance with her again,
我大概就会记得她
I'd probably recognize her.
很好你在这里找她
Great That takes care of everything but finding her.
就容易多了  为何问我她的长像呢
You were here. Why ask me how she looked?
我只有看到她的背影
I only saw her from the back.
她长的大概是这么  她有一个
She was a...about this... She had a...
如果再看到她的背影
If I ever saw her from the back again,
我会认出来
I'd recognize her.
好啊  只要再跟她跳次舞
Viol, that's fine. After I've danced with her,
我让她转圈给你看好吗
I just turn her around for your okay.
这很简单的
This should be a cinch.
你看过她
You saw her.
-描述一下  -谁我吗
-Describe her. -Who, me?
没有很近的看到她
Well, I wasn't watching very closely.
她大概是中等身材
She was a medium...medium-built sort of a girl
就像一般大众脸的女孩
with a medium face.
她穿了件很迷人的晚礼服
She had a...a nice evening gown on
背后系了跟带子
with a belt in the back.
她的身材跟我女朋友的差不多
She was built just like a girlfriend of mine,
一个未曾谋识的女孩  但是
a girl you don't know, but...
她名字是  康苏拉史勒凯斯
her name was Consuela Schlepkiss.
她喜欢在超商里面打电动玩具
She used to play the pinball machine at the drugstore.
她真的很热门呢  三星期才排到我
She was high man three weeks in a row.
谢谢你  多谢了
Thank you. Thanks a lot.
没什么啦  很乐意为你服务
That's nothing at all. Happy to do it for you.
我有个预感呢  各位
Say, I've got a hunch, fellas,
最后一定会找到这女孩的
we're gonna find this girl eventually.
当找到时  一定能满足我们的期待
And when we do, we'll be glad we waited for her.
真的  我对寻找其他搭档
Listen, I'm not interested in
没什么兴趣懂吗
getting any other partner, understand?
一次夜晚神奇的懈遘
A chance meeting in the night.
她会回来的
Destiny. She'll be back
下次假期在这里会找到她的
Here's where we'll find her on the next holiday.
这里  这里
-Here? -Here.
我要去翻烤牛排了
I've got to go turn the roast.
二月
林肯生日
你别担心了  我们会找到他的
Now don't worry. We'll find her.
如果我看到她的背影
If I see her from the back again,
就会认出来的
I'll recognize her.
看来像双向道
It's kind of a roundabout way
但还是试试看吧
to go at it, but let's try it.
你有空吗
Are you decent?
是的  请进
Yes, come in.
那是什么  我想过了
-What's that? -Well, I thought it over,
如果用黑脸数字可能会更好
and I believe our number would go better in blackface.
我以为这样做就可以了
Oh, I thought we were gonna do it like this.
那是过去我  在我想通之前
Well, that was before I...before I thought it over.
-这样我看来很恐怖呢  -不
-I'll look terrible in the stuff. -No.
怎么加上去我都不会呢
I don't even know how to put it on.
我帮你涂上去吧
I'll put it on for you.
这样好像黑皮鞋一样
I broke in as a bootblack, you know.
开始啦
Here we go.
过去一个半月以来
Oh! For a month and a half...
我一直幻想今晚我有多美呢
I've been dreaming how pretty I was going to look tonight.
这就是对自己过多幻想的惩罚
Well, here's my punishment for thinking so well of myself.
要美机会还有很多呢
Oh, you'll have plenty of times to be pretty.
我正想要问你
I was just going to ask you
其它的节目不知会怎样
to be in the rest of the shows out here.
-你有吗  -你会吗
-You were? -Will you?
我会吗  一年有十五个夜晚
Will I? Fifteen nights a year...
灰姑娘进入南瓜马车里面
Cinderella steps into her pumpkin coach
变成了假日酒店里的皇后
and becomes Queen of Holiday Inn.
怎么了
What's the matter?
希望其它的
I wish I didn't have to work
假期不必工作
all the other days in the year...
让这一切变成可能
to make these few possible.
也许过一阵子  我们会有更好表现
Maybe a little later on when we start doing better,
你可以一直待在这里
you can stay out here all the time.
你知道刚才说了什么吗
Did you hear what you just said?
-是的  -那是个计划吗
-Yeah. -Was it a proposal?
只要银行里多点钱  就能实现
Well, it will be when I get a few bucks in the bank.
你真是只怪鸭子
Well, you're a strange duck.
不给我说答令的机会
You  don't  even  give  me  a  chance  to  say  "Darling"
就抓着我的手臂跟着你
and throw my arms around you.
等银行存款多些再说吧
You'd better save that till you see the bank book.
我想这就是订婚了
Well, I guess I'm sort of engaged.
这是什么啊  小雏菊链子
Say, what is this, a daisy chain?
我们在欣赏陌生女子的背影
we were just looking for the back of a girl we don't know.
在二月的清晨
Upon a February morn
一位小婴儿诞生
A tiny baby boy was born
亚伯拉罕
Abraham
当他长到这么大的时候
When he gnawed up this tiny babe
人们都称呼他诚实亚伯
Folks all called him Honest Abe
亚伯拉罕
Abraham
在1860年他成为
In 1860 he became
第十六任总统
The 16th president
他现在立在名人堂里
And now he's in the Hall of Fame
最尊敬的伟人
A most respected gent
所以我们要纪念
That's why we celebrate
这伟大的二月生日
This blessed February date
亚伯拉罕
Abraham
当黑人同胞奴隶般生活
When black folks lived in slavery
是他解放黑奴自由
Who was it set the darky free
-亚伯拉罕  -对的  孩子
-Abraham -That's right, child.
亚伯拉罕
Abraham
当麻烦从山崖降下
When troubles come down from the shelf
有谁比他更大的心胸
Whose heart was bigger than hisself
-亚伯拉罕  -好吃
-Abraham -Yeah, man!
亚伯拉罕
Abraham
全国变成了u狗
The country's going to the dogs
对他强烈发出怒吼
They shouted loud and strong
从一个肥皂箱子上
Then from a cabin made out of logs
有个人挺身而出
The right man came along
这就是我们为何要纪念
And that is why we celebrate
这伟大的二月诞生日
This blessed February date
亚伯拉罕
Abraham
感谢美国的创建
U.S.A.'s united thanks
-大家都知道她名字南西翰克  -说
-To one whose name was Nancy Hanks -Tell me!
亚伯拉罕
Abraham
她送给这片土地最好的儿子
She gave this land the finest son
这是她的成就
That's what she did.
-是谁到了华盛顿  -是谁
-Whoever went to Washington -Who dat?
亚伯拉罕
Abraham
当有人跟他说葛兰将军
When someone told him General Grant
每夜酗酒不断
Was drinking every night
他回答到  你出去
He answered Go on out, see if you can't
看能否让我将军们都收敛
Get all my generals tight
-亚  -所以我们要庆祝
-A... -That's why we celebrate
-伯  -这伟大的二月诞生日
-Bra... -This blessed February date
-罕  -亚伯拉罕
-Ham -Abraham
是个真正的好人  就是亚伯拉罕
Was a real fine man, that Abraham
亚伯拉罕
Abraham
他是个伟人  伟大的人
Was a great man, great man
亚伯拉罕
Abraham
晚安
Good night.
我放弃了  她今晚不在场
I give up. She's not here tonight.
你在这里等  我上去问吉姆是否见到她
You wait here. I'll go up and see if Jim's seen her.
贾斯等着送你到车站
Gus is waiting to take you to the station.
记住后天是情人节
Romanian, day after tomorrow, St. Valentino's Day.
有人来了  走其它楼梯吧
Someone's coming. Use the other stairway.
-是谁啊  -讨债者啊
-Well, who is it? -Bill collector.
-晚安  -晚安吉姆
-Good night. -Good night, Jim.
还没感冒前快进去吧
You'd better get inside before you catch cold.
你没有穿外套呢
You haven't got a coat.
-我  -快点啊
-Well, I... -Go on.
我不需要穿外套
I don't need a coat now.
泰德  有没找到那女孩
Hey, Ted, did you find the girl?
真糟糕我希望在前门
This is terrible.
能认出她的模样
I wish we could recognize her from the front.
-我好像匹狼一样  -泰德
-I feel like a wolf. -Ted!
泰德
Ted!
Ted
她在这里  我看到她了  往这里走吧
She's here! I saw her! This way! Let go!
谁
Who?
捷径啊  捷径啊  快点啊
Shortcut, Shortcut, come on!
走吧
Giddap!
怎么上锁了  以前从没有锁起来呢
Why, it's locked. It's never been locked before.
老天
Oh, me!
我们走其它楼梯吧
Let's try the other stairway.
-放开我  -请便
-Let go of me! -Go ahead.
又找不到她了
Well, we've lost her again.
这次有看见她的脸吗
Did you get a look at her face this time?
没有  我们还在朝背后努力
No. We're still working from the rear.
你怎么确定就是她呢  她有穿件外套啊
How do you know it was her? She had an overcoat on.
我不管她穿了什么
I don't care if she ha...
你怎么知道她有穿外套
How do you know she had an overcoat on?
她啊  她看来像
Well, she...If she didn't,
得肺炎一样呢
look for a girl with pneumonia.
走吧我们进去吧
Come on, let's get inside.
我说啊  吉姆  下场表演是什么时候
Say, um, Jim, when's your next show?
下一场秀  我想应该是情人节吧
Next show? eh, St. Valentine's Day, I think.
-后天  -是吗
-Ooh, the day after tomorrow, huh? -Is it?
中间有空档  我们可以早点到
That's a break. We'll get here early
等着她的出现
and stay until we find her.
我们会要求她
We'll make an announcement
表明自己身份
asking her to identify herself.
下次不会再错过了
We won't miss next time.
兄弟们节目喜欢吗
No. Fellas, how'd you like the show?
我们很忙没时间多看呢
Well, we were so busy we didn't see
为何问呢
much of it, Jim. Why?
我想观众
Thought the people seemed to like
喜欢看黑脸呢
the blackface routine.
是啊  他们喜欢
Yeah, they did.
你不觉得黑脸打扮
Don't you think a blackface umber
在情人节不适合吗
on St. Valentine's Day?! be novel?
不怎样
A what?
不太好对吗  只是我的想法
It's no good, huh? Just an idea I had.
-再见  -再见  泰德
-Well, good-bye. -Good-bye, Ted.
再见啦吉姆
So long, Jim.
二月
情人节
-小姐  -是的
-Hey, lady! -Yes?
一小时后演出  你还没有排练呢
We open in an hour. You haven't even had a rehearsal.
来了
Coming.
很美嘛
Oh, very smart.
你要跟盖斯说
You'll have to talk Gus
买个无马的马车呢
into buying a horseless carriage.
从车站到这里  花了我半生的时间
I spend half my life between here and the station.
盖斯要面对机器时代
Gus'll have to face the machine age
早晚将会来临对吗
sooner or later, won't he?
前天晚上你在躲避债主吗
Did you escape those bill collectors the other night?
债主
Bill colle...
是的  你倒临时提醒我
Oh, yes, temporarily. That reminds me,
我有个惊喜给你在楼下
I got a surprise for you downstairs.
-多谢了提醒你什么  -没什么
-Well, thanks. What reminds you? -Nothing.
就是  你要记得当讨债鬼来时
It's just, uh, I want you to remember the surprise...
我就会给你一个惊喜
when those doggone bill collectors move in.
声音很甜美  但没什么道理呢
You sound sweet, but you don't make sense.
酒店真的很浪曼呢
Oh, the Inn is so romantic-looking!
这些是我自己挑选的呢
I posed for those Cupids myself.
-哈罗孩子们  -哈罗琳达  嗨吉姆
-Hello, boys. -Hello, Linda. Hi, Jim.
今晚有许多帐要付呢
A lot of paid-up cards here tonight.
-惊喜在哪里  -在这里啊
-Where's the surprise? -Aha, right here.
我自己煮的家常菜
A little home cooking I whipped up.
太美了
Beautiful.
小心是我的芳心
"Be Careful It's My Heart."
我不再是个小女孩
And I ain't kidding either.
这是我为你写的甜心
I wrote this just for you, honey.
小心点
Be careful
这是我芳心
It's my heart
你拥有的不是我的手表
It's not my watch you're holding
是我的芳心
It's my heart
不是送你的纸条
It's not the note I sent you
可以随意烧毁
That you quickly burned
不是我借你的书本
It's not the book I lent you
可以永远不还
That you never returned
记住
Remember
是我的芳心
It's my heart
发自我全心意的芳心
The heart with which so willingly I part
送给你保存或破坏
It's yours to take to keep or break
但在你开始前请记住
But please before you start
要小心
Be careful
因为是我的芳心
It's my heart
就是那女孩
That's the girl.
要小心
Be careful
是我的芳心
It's my heart
不是你拥有我的手表
It's not my watch you're holding
是我的芳心
It's my heart
不是我写给你的纸条
It's not the note I sent you
可以随意烧毁
That you quickly burned
不是我借给你的书本
It's not the book I lent you
可以永不归还
That you never returned
记住
Remember
是我的芳心
It's my heart
是我全心全意付出的芳心
The heart with which so willingly I part
让你保存或破坏
It's yours to take to keep or break
但在开始前请记住
But please before you start
要小心
Be careful
因为那是我芳心
It's my heart
抱歉吉姆  我无法抗拒呢
Sorry, Jim, I couldn't resist it.
太棒了  她太完美了  如同羽毛般轻盈
Wonderful! She's perfect. Light as a feather.
你找到她了  吉姆  你是个好兄弟
You found her. Jim, you're a pal.
是啊
Yeah!
你知道我们找你数周了吗
Do you realize we've been searching for you for weeks?
-找我  -是的  自从
-For me? -Yes! Ever since...
-花店里的女孩  -是的  瑞德先生
-The girl in the flower shop. -Yes, Mr. Reed.
新年除夕到现在  你在哪里工作啊
Where have you been working since New Year's Eve?
这里
Here.
你愿意让我进入  你的秘密里
Would you mind letting me in on your secret?
没什么秘密
It's no secret.
泰德・汉诺瓦在找一位新搭档
Ted Hanover is looking for a new dancing partner.
我们决定这个工作给你
We've decided to give you the job.
等一下
Now wait just a minute!
没恶意的  吉姆
No hard feelings, Jim.
我不怪你如此痴情  她太棒了
I don't blame you for trying. She's wonderful.
我觉得认识她好像很久了
I feel as if I'd known her for months.
感觉又找到了吗
Oh, same old feeling, huh?
下场秀是华盛顿纪念日
Washington's birthday is the next show.
还有一个星期彩排时间
That'll give us a week rehersals.
我们可以在此演出
We can open the act here.
我负责发邀请函
I'll take care of the invitations.
绝对的正式
Strictly formal.
我会让纽约所有报社都到齐
I'll get all the newspaper boys from New York.
一切且慢
Hold everything.
这是我的酒店我不想
This is my inn and I'm not running it
找一群不相干的人到场
for a bunch of stuffed shirts.
你觉得唐嘉利怎样  比那个你找来的
What would you like, the dungaree set?
大笨蛋
That'd be better than that
好多了
bunch of chowderheads you'd drag in.
也许我不该用那个表演
Maybe I can't use the act.
不表演吗泰德・汉诺瓦
Not use Ted Hanover?
秀已经准备好了呢
Well, the show is pretty well set.
可以用你但他出局了
You're in, but he's out.
特别日子
You could change the show for
可以做些调整啊
a special occasion like this.
当然他可以
Of course he could.
他只是想隐藏他的感激
He's just trying to hide his gratitude.
吉姆  你要为我们节目着想
Jim, you'd better think up a number for us.
你预测了什么吗怪人
Well, just what do you visualize, Ziggy?
我想想看啊
Uh, let's see, um...
华盛顿纪念日节目中
For Washington's birthday,
我看到了浪曼服装之类的
I see a sort of a romantic costume thing.
当然啦
Naturally.
跟优雅
Something that just
和迷人有关
reeks with grace and charm,
-你了解吗  -是的
-you know. -Mm-hmm.
我想音乐应该
I think the music
温柔而且缓慢
should be sweet and gentle to...
营造一种每当我将她
well, to create the mood each time
拥入怀抱亲吻的气芬
I take her into my arms and kiss her.
就这样
That's it.
不觉得这里有点拥挤了吗
Don't you think it's getting a little stuffy in here?
二月
二十二日
华盛顿生日
我可以说你爱家园
I could say that you're homely
就像个派一样
Just as homely as pie
但今天是华盛顿纪念日
But this is Washington's birthday
我必需承认你很美丽
And I've got to say You're beautiful
因我从不说谎
Cause I can't tell a lie
我会说你很傻
I could say that you're stupid
你的皇冠上什么都没有
Nothing up in your crown
但今天是华圣顿纪念日
But this is Washington's birthday
他对樱桃树的诚实
And the truthful he of the cherry tree
我的行为也是一样
Would look down on me and frown
我很想说我恨你
I could say that I hate you
如果我尝试
If I try
但我必需说我爱你
But I've got to say I love you
因为今天是二月二十二日
Cause it's February the 22nd
我不能说谎
And I can't tell a lie
音乐
Hit it!
进来
Come in!
除了好朋友
In spite of what
吉姆的帮忙
good old Jim tried to do to us,
你的前途就从今晚开始
your future starts as of tonight.
你打算从此地出发到哪里
Now, where would you like to go from here?
从此地出发
From here?
是的纽约哈瓦那里约
Yes. New York? Havana? Rio?
我们有过协议呢
We have our pick of engagements.
如果你离开酒店
But I can't be your partner
我无法成为你搭档
if you leave the Inn.
当然可以
Of course you can.
没有理由
There's no reason
你要继续待在这里
for you to remain buried here.
我有充份的理由
There's a very good reason.
我已经答应吉姆
I've promised to be in Jim's
演完今年所有的假期
holiday shows for the rest of the year.
他为了躲避我
He tricked you into that
所以才设计你
while he was hiding you from me.
不论他怎么做我已答应他了
No matter how he did it, I promised.
而且我们已经
Besides, we're...
我们打算要结婚了
Well, we're going to be married.
结婚
Married?
等一等  公平一点嘛
Now wait a minute! Let's be fair.
他连机会都没有给我呢
He didn't give me a chance.
而且我也爱你呢
After all, I love you too.
从我们共舞的那刻就爱上你
From the very first moment we danced together,
我知道你是我今生的女孩
I knew you were to be the one girl in my life.
但是你  你连我名字都不知道
But you...you didn't even know my name.
拜托你好吧  忘了我
Please! All right. Forget about me, then.
也忘了吉姆吧
Forget about Jim.
为自己想想  你有机会
Think of yourself. Here's your chance to
为自己做最好的选择
do the one thing you like best.
不仅一年十五天而是永远
Not only for 15 days a year, but always.
抱歉但我答应了
Sorry, but I promised.
我想我该为打扰你搭档
Well, I guess I should apologize for
而向你道歉罗
hoking up your number, huh?
别说了
Oh, forget it. I'm the one
我才该向你道歉
that should apologize to you.
我一直想把琳达
Here I've been trying to
从你身边带走
take Linda away from you,
不知道你们两位要结婚了
not knowing you two were going to be married.
结婚
Married?
是的  不是吗
Yeah. Aren't you?
是的当然啦
Yes. Sure. Uh...
我是说很自然的  我们像订过婚了
I mean, naturally we're sort of engaged.
反正我已经打算离开这里
Well, um, anyway, I've decided to bow out of here.
琳达是你的了
Linda's all yours.
你真的很会玩游戏呢
Viol, you're a pretty game guy to take it this way.
时常发生我也习惯了
It's happened so often I'm getting
就这样吧
used to it, that's all.
-再见啦  小鬼  -祝你好运  泰德
-Good-bye, kid. -Lot of luck, Ted.
谢了
Thanks.
怎样了
How are we doing?
两分钟前  我会将机会
Two minutes ago, I would've sold my chances
以两毛钱卖出去
for a tired dime.
但当一个男人意外的听到
But when a man is surprised to hear
自己将要结婚时
that he's going to be married,
当我自己遇到明显的巧合
that's when I go to work with a clear conscience.
-一切都美好吗  -一切都很完美
-Everything's good, huh? -Everything is perfect.
四月
复活节日
你的复活节小帽
In your Easter bonnet
上面有各种装饰
With all the frills upon it
你将是复活节游行
You'll be the grandest lady
最端庄的淑女
In the Easter Parade
我将会很有面子
I'll be all in clover
当她们注视你时
And when they look you over
我是最骄傲的男人
I'll be the proudest fella
在复活节游行
In the Easter Parade
在大街上
On the Avenue
第五大道上
Fifth Avenue
摄影师为我们拍照
The photographers will snap us
你将会发现自己
And you'll find that you're
在报纸的首页
In the rotogravure
我
Oh, I
可以写十四行诗
Could write a sonnet
关于你的复活节帽
About your Easter bonnet
还有跟我一齐参加
And of the girl I'm taking
复活节游行的女孩
To the Easter Parade
在大街上
On the Avenue
第五大道上
Fifth Avenue
摄影师为我们拍照
The photographers will snap us
你将发现自己
And you'll find that you're
在报纸的首页
In the rotogravure
我
Oh, I
可以写十四行诗
Could write a sonnet
关于你的复活节帽
About your Easter bonnet
还有跟我一齐参加
And of the girl I'm taking
复活节游行的女孩
To the Easter Parade
哈罗
Hello
我没准备欢迎踏垫
I didn't exactly expect the welcome mat,
但我想某人会打招呼
but I thought somebody might say hello.
-哈罗  -谢谢
-Hello -Thanks
什么风把你吹来的  在这明亮未邀请的日子
What brings you here on this bright and uninviting day?
我发现了些事  好朋友有关人生
I've discovered something, my friends, about life.
-指的是什么呢  -我不想要成名
-Meaning what? -Well, I don't want success.
我要真正的幸福
I want the true happiness
你们在酒店可以找到
you people have found here at the Inn.
你不想待在酒店了吗
You're not gonna stay in the Inn?
不仅待在这  我还想成为
Not just stay. I want to be part of
工作伙伴  帮你发展事业
your shows, help you in your work,
分担你的快乐
share your simple pleasures.
我命令你不要介入  泰德
I asked you once not to interfere, Ted.
拜托请相信我  我是个疲惫孤独又无趣的人
Please believe me, I'm a tired, lonely and unhappy man,
但我在这里很快乐
but I could be happy here
我喜欢帮助最爱的两个人
helping the two people I like the best.
-你会让我加入吗  -我的母爱本能
-Will you take me in? -My motherly intuition
告诉我赶他走呢
tells me to throw him out.
致少要给他应有的答案
Well, at least give him the benefit of the doubt.
我给了他足够的答案
I've given him plenty of doubt.
你在开玩笑
Are you kidding with that
分享单纯的快乐
"sharing life's simple pleasures"?
-我能跟你进去吗  -当然
-May I go inside with you? -of course.
我的卡车今天下午会到
My trunks will arrive this afternoon.
我该怎么办住进抽屉里
What do I do, move in the broom closet?
这样跟帮你的男人讲太差了
That's no way to talk to a man who's here to help you.
世界不会有所改变
The world doesn't change.
一个微笑会改变一切
A gentle smile often breeds a kick in the pants,
但为你好我宁愿努力
but for your sake I'll be big.
七月
独立纪念日
我会给你小费的
I'll give you a tip about these things,
但你往前又往后  我不会在路上给的
They'll go up and back, but not sideways.
我努力记得这一切
I keep forgetting this blamed thing
但不知道它要往哪里
can't see where it's going.
把东西从后面来下来吧
Yeah. Well, unload the rest of this stuff in the back, huh?
好的
Yeah.
还没吃早餐起来干什么
What'd you do, get up before breakfast?
每天早上
Oh, every morning.
我发现你很晚才回来
When I found out how late you got in,
就告诉曼妮让你睡
I told Mamie to let you sleep.
-农场的生活  -无法适应对吗
-Life on a farm. -Can't beat it, huh?
-吉姆我真的很快乐  -很好
-Jin, you've made me very happy. -That's fine.
-你也让我快乐  -你口气像房东
-How about you making me happy? -You sound like a landlord
在下逐客令呢
with eviction papers.
这是个好消息  丽拉回到纽约
This is good news. Lila's back in New York.
我接到她的信
I got a letter from her.
她的百万富翁怎样了
What happened to her millionaire?
有点小错误
Slight mistake there.
他不是百万富翁  他欠了百万
He didn't own millions, he owed them.
可怜的女孩
Poor girl.
待在绿荫的牧草里
Always straying to gamer pastures
-寻找波菜  -是啊
-and finding spinach. -Yeah.
她在想你是否有兴趣
She was wondering if you'd be interested in
担任她音乐搭档
taking her back as a partner.
-这个主意很好  -当然你可以去
-I think it'd be a great idea. -Naturally, you would.
我喜欢在这里跟你和琳达一起
But I like it here with you and Linda.
是的我们也喜欢跟你一起
Yes, we love having you too.
你何时离开
Uh, when are you leaving?
老天
Oh. Oh.
-你为什么不说话呢  -看起来很傻呢
-Why didn't you say something? -You look so silly.
-吉姆呢  -在里面
-Where's Jim? -Inside.
很好我搞定了
Good. I fixed it.
新闻上有夸张的大字  好莱坞
Here's the news in one luscious word: Hollywood.
跟你说了我不走
I told you I'm not leaving
除非琳达跟我一起走
until Linda goes with me.
但我们安排好的
But this is the setup
你要让她离开吉姆
you needed to get her away from Jim.
今晚有两个
There're gonna be two Hollywood men
好莱坞人光临
here tonight to see the show.
一位是导演呢
One's an important director.
如果他们喜欢你的舞蹈
If they like your dancing,
你跟琳达明天就在火车上了
you and Linda will be on a train tomorrow.
看看琳达是否有兴趣
We'd better find out if Linda's interested.
如果有合约要让她知道
We let her know when there's a contract
-让她成名呢  -听着
-staring her in the face. -Look
我知道你在恋爱  但不管它
I know you're in love with the girl but forget it
直到我们让她离开他为止
until we get her away from him.
-现在不是诚实的时刻  -我该怎么办
-This is no time to be honest. -Well, what should I do?
我们该说服吉姆  如果他介入
We have to convince Jim that he'd be a heel if he stood
就像现在一样毫无机会
in the way of a chance like this.
这很容易  等于打倒一只乌龟
Well, that'll be easy. Like peeling a turtle.
-妈咪说这些放在上面  -是的  把它们摆好
-Mamie says these go up here. -Yes. Set them right down.
盖斯  你想要赚十块钱吗
Say, Gus, how'd you like to earn a slow $10?
不管怎么赚但一定要有
Don't care how slow, but sure.
当然会有  细节是这样
It's sure, all right. Here's the wrinkle:
你到火车站去
I want you to go to the station,
接个人回到酒店
pick up a party and start for Holiday Inn,
但不要带回这里
but never get here.
-可以处理吗  -没什么难的
-Could you handle that? -Wouldn't be surprised.
哈罗  长途台
Hello? Long distance.
我要你对琳达・梅生这么做
That's what I want you to do with Linda Mason.
梅生小姐  我们的朋友
Miss Mason? Our friend?
你会懂这些细节的
You're not supposed to understand it, Gus.
有了这些钱你可以
With that kind of money,
去买一顶好帽子了
you oughta be able to go by way of Medicine Hat.
哈罗  是的  等一等
Hello? Yeah. Just a minute.
长途吗  我要接纽约市公园饭店
Long distance. I want to get Parkway Hotel, New York City.
琳达・梅生小姐
Miss Lila Dixon.
琳达小姐没说要过来排演
Didn't Linda say she'd be here for rehearsal?
别紧张  我们观众没有太高要求的
Oh, relax. Our audiences aren't professional critics.
-盖斯你转错了  -捷径
-Gus, you made a wrong turn. -Shortcut.
-盖斯  -捷径接捷径
-Gus! -Shortcut... to the shortcut.
你怎么这样开车
How could you possibly expect to drive through this?
我骑马都不会这样呢
I never had no trouble with a horse.
你最好带我到海边
You'd better carry me to shore,
我再走回高速公路
and I'll walk back to the highway.
我想你最好待在这里等待
I think you'd be better off waiting right here.
盖斯请照我的话做好吗
Gus, will you please do as I say?
好的
Oh, all right.
另一条路转弯
The other way!
转弯啊  盖斯  转弯啊
Turn around! Gus, turn around!
盖斯
Gus!
我的帽子
My hat!
-是你推我的  -去找我的帽子
-Ya pushed me! -Get my hat!
表演马上就要开始了
I swear the show will start any minute now.
一小时前你就说过了
You said that an hour ago.
是的  但现在我很确定呢
Yeah, but this time I'm sincere.
打扰了
Excuse me.
-秀谁先上场  -是我该你上了
-Who started the show? -I did. You're on.
-泰德的搭档怎办  -你让观众
-What about Ted's partner? -You've kept
等太久了
this crowd waiting long enough.
-没有她也能上场的  -你疯了吗
-He can go on without her. -Have you gone nuts?
我排演了双人舞呢
I rehearsed a double dance!
我们以鞭炮和彩带
Let's say it with firecrackers
飘上天空
And banners held high
我们以传统的方式
Let's have a real old-fashioned
欢度七月四日
Noisy Fourth of July
我们以鞭炮和彩带
Let's say it with firecrackers
从南方传到北方
Down south and up north
让我们以熟悉方式  迎接光辉的四日
Let's have the kind we used to call a Glorious Fourth
我们向自己的土地致敬
Let's salute our native land
每人手上执着蜡
Roman candles in each hand
一队洋基乐队
While a Yankee Doodle band
比鞭炮还来的响亮
Gets hotter than a firecracker
不需要任何壅长演说
Don't need any long speeches
或大声呼叫万岁
Or shouts of hooray
没有话语比鞭炮声更响亮
No words can say as much as firecrackers can say
自由
Freedom
自由的人类出现了
Here comes the Freedom Man
这个独立的日子
On this day of independence
On this Independence Day
听着美国号角
Listen to an American troubadour
传遍整个美国大地
From the USA.
我唱首自由的歌曲
I'm singing a song of freedom
为所有得到自由而哭泣的人们
For all people who cry out to be free
自由的出海七洋
Free to sail the seven seas
自由的前往做礼拜
Free to worship as we please
如果树上的鸟儿有自由
If the birds up in the trees can be free
人们也该享有
Why can't we
我带来一首自由的歌曲
I'm bringing a song of freedom
送给所有需要自由的人
To all people wherever they may be
说话的自由  聆听的自由
Free to speak and free to hear
需求的自由  和免于恐惧自由
Free from want and free from fear
儿童的自由  远近都不是问题
Sons of freedom far and near who agree
跟我一同唱
Sing with me
上帝的子民都该有自由
That all God's people shall be free
我唱一首自由的歌曲
I'm singing a song of freedom
为所有争取自由的人哭泣
For all people who cry out to be free
自由的航向七海
Free to sail the seven seas
自由的前往做礼拜
Free to worship as we please
如果树上的鸟儿有自由
If the birds up in the trees can be free
人类也该享有
Why can't we
我唱一首自由的歌曲
I'm singing a song of freedom
送给所有想要自由的人们
To all people wherever they may be
说话的自由  与聆听的自由
Free to speak and free to hear
需求的自由  与免于恐惧自由
Free from want and free from fear
儿童的自由  远近都不是问题
Sons of freedom far and near who agree
跟着我唱
Sing with me
上帝的子民都该有自由
That all God's people shall be free
-让我离开好吗  -上来吧
-Will you give me a lift? -Sure. Hop in.
你是泰德・汉诺瓦前任搭档
Aren't you Ted Hanover's former dancing partner?
是的虽然我不会说前任
Yes, although I wouldn't exactly say "former"?
今晚我跟他都在酒店
I'm dancing with him at the Inn tonight.
但我  他不是有新搭档了吗
But I...Doesn't he have a new partner?
她今晚不会来的
Oh, she won't be there tonight.
我不晓得呢  我在酒店工作
I didn't know that. I...I work at the Inn.
服务生吗
Oh? Waitress?
-是的  -我认识你老板吉姆・哈弟
-Yes. -I know your boss, Jim Hardy,
很熟呢
quite well.
很熟
Quite well.
他负责你的回答吗
He's responsible for your
-汉诺瓦先生  -是的
-rejoining Mr. Hanover? -Uh-huh.
还有如果我是你
By the way, if I were you,
今晚我会打扮最漂亮
I'd look my prettiest tonight.
吉姆说今天好莱坞有人光临
Jim says there'll be men there from Hollywood
帮泰德和我照像
to consider Ted and me for pictures.
汉诺瓦另一搭档
Mr. Hanover's other partner
将错失好莱坞发展的机会
will be missing this chance to go to Hollywood.
是的  虽然她才华不太出色
Yes, although she can't be very talented
否则也不会在酒店工作
or they wouldn't be working at the Inn.
泰德跟我只在最棒地点演出
Ted and I played only the best places.
真的你的秀要延迟了
Listen, you're late for the show already.
如果你能让我开车  我知道有条捷径
If you'd care to let me drive, I know a shortcut
可以早十五分钟到呢
that'll get us there 15 minutes sooner.
农场就在这附近
There's a farmhouse near here,
几分钟之内就可以到达
and I'll have us towed out in a couple of minutes.
-就算走泥地也可以  -你在这里等着
-For the love of mud, hurry! -Wait right here!
我还有选择吗
What else can I do?
该你上场了
You're on now.
-但琳达还没到  -必需救救这里
-But Linda isn't here yet. -You've got to save the pieces.
让那些人提起兴趣
Keep those men interested now
呆会再进行琳达的部份
and do a number with Linda later.
-我能干什么呢  -模仿一些吧
-What can I do? -Well, fake something.
模仿一些东西
Fake something.
你在这里啊  别耍我了  快飞啊
There's your cue! Don't fail me! Keep them flying!
我会让它飞的
I'll keep them flying.
-琳达  你是怎么了  -不满工作罢工
-Linda! What happened to you? -Bad job of sabotage.
对不起
Excuse me.
吉姆  今晚你应该跟我
Jim, you deliberately kept me
在酒店表演的对吗
from working at the Inn tonight, didn't you?
是的
Yeah.
你知道今晚这里有好莱坞的人到场
You knew there would be men here from Hollywood
会有帮我拍照的机会
who might offer me a chance in pictures.
你觉得我不该有这机会吗
You decided I shouldn't have that opportunity,
甚至连拒绝得机会都不该
not even the opportunity to refuse.
我害怕报酬对你太重要
I was afraid the offer might be
而加以回绝
too important for you to turn down.
重点是你不相信我
The point is you don't trust me
对自己的决定
to make my own decisions...
因为他们可能会破坏  你自私的计划
because they might interfere with your own selfish plans.
我对吉姆的一切已无法忍受
I've had about enough of that, Jim.
泰德  琳达
Ted! Linda!
派克先生  登堡先生  我来介绍最伟大的
Mr. Parker, Mr. Dunbar, I want you to meet
秀场舞蹈搭档
the greatest dance team in show business
汉诺瓦与梅生  还有老板吉姆・哈弟
Hanover and Mason and the owner, Jim Hardy.
你这里很不错嘛
Nice little place you've got here.
虽然没看过梅生小姐的舞蹈
Even though you haven't seen Miss Mason dance,
但我敢跟你保证
I can assure you...
哈弟  好莱坞一向对新点子
Hardy, Hollywood is always interested in new ideas
有兴趣而我们想这很好呢
and we think this is a honey.
我们想以假日酒店为背景  拍些照片
We'd like to do a picture based on Holiday Inn.
点子的背后显示出
The idea behind it, how it works,
特殊假期歌曲的特色
the special holiday songs.
它真是一很特殊的东西
It's purely a speculative thing,
一般很少见  我们无法付太高代价
far from foolproof, and we can't afford to pay too much.
你不用开始就拒绝
You don't have to start talking it down
因为这点子是非卖品
because the idea is not for sale.
或许我没有解释清楚
Maybe I haven't explained enough.
我们希望能采用汉诺瓦先生  和他搭档的照片
We expect to use Mr. Hanover and his partner in the picture.
我不知其它人的感觉
I don't know how the others feel,
但我喜欢这种主题
but I'd like to keep this setup
真的十分自然
just the way it is.
吉姆你可以大方一次
Jim, would you be decent just once
给这里的其它人一次机会
and let somebody else here have a chance?
等等  丹尼
Wait a minute, Danny.
这里属于他  他可随心所欲
The place belongs to him. He can do as he wants.
我想这一切都太迟了吧
I guess it was just too good to last, huh?
一个单纯的画面
A simple little layout
我们可发挥淋离尽至
where we could do our best at the work we know...
不必任何光辉的说明
without having any illusions of glory.
但我可以看的出
But I can see now
这里只有我很快乐
that I'm the only one who could be happy here.
继续  拍这些点子拍音乐
Go ahead, take the idea. Take the music,
拍琳达  拍所有好的东西
take Linda, take the whole darned thing.
但是你呢
But what about you?
但我们好莱坞需要你
But we'll need you in Hollywood
完成其馀的音乐
to write the rest of the music.
不行  我在这里工作
Oh, no. I work right here.
写完后我再寄给你听吧
I'll send you the music when it's written.
没写完别来烦我
And don't bother me before, huh?
这样我有点自私吧
I guess maybe I was a little selfish, huh?
你需要这种方式
Is that the deal you wanted,
还是我丢出自己的衬衫
or should I have thrown in my shirt?
他很可爱对吧
Chummy sort of a fella, isn't he?
说真的琳达  如果你真的想待在这里
Listen, Linda, if you really want to stay here...
别这种口气讲话
Don't talk that way!
这是你想要的机会不是吗
This is the chance you wanted, isn't it?
当然  老天我们真快乐
Of course! Boy, are we happy!
复活节快乐  吉姆先生
Happy Thanksgiving, Mr. Jim.
你也一样妈咪  还有员工们
Same to you, Mamie... and staff.
你没叫孩子们待在厨房吗
Didn't I tell you children to stay in the kitchen?
这些翅膀飞不掉的
Those wings ain't gonna fly away.
快走
Now shoo! Git!
一切都准备好了  吉姆先生
Everything's ready and hot, Mr. Jim.
谢谢  你妈咪
Thank you, Mamie.
有太多需要感谢的了
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
我没有大的游艇
行驶在海的两岸
但是还是有太多需要感谢
你装满了老爸
You're loaded, Dad.
我有太多需要感谢的地方
例如呢
Like what?
没有私家车  没有鱼子酱
我的地板上没有地毯
但是还是有太多需要感谢
说真的  你比我好的太多
You know, you're better off than I am.
我有眼睛可以看
I've got eyes to see with
你需要戴眼镜
You need glasses.
有耳朵可以听
Ears to hear with
或者飞翔
Or fly with.
有手臂可拥抱  嘴巴可以亲吻
别人也羡慕
你有点胖
You're a little flat too.
人们怎能不满足呢
我的要求不多  我可以买下
五分一角店的所有东西
唱吧
Sing it.
我有太多要感谢的了
好好地唱吧
Sing it pretty.
-你没有被咬到  -我生气了妈咪
-Why, you ain't et a bite. -I'm pouting, Mamie.
-这位是谁  -他是琼斯先生
-Who is this? -That's Mr. Jones.
琼希  真抱歉  我跟他太熟啦
Jonesy? I'm sorry. I knew him too well.
但你必需吞下所有的麻烦
But you've got to eat.
不是那只火鸡  而是你
The trouble ain't with that turkey. It's you!
我觉得很好  我骑的很快妈咪
I feel all right. I'm riding high, Mamie.
为何不关上酒店  像水母般
Why'd you close the Inn and sit around like
跟我一起坐下来呢
a jellyfish with the misery?
因为一个骗子偷了你马子
Cause a slicker stole your gal
你没有勇气把她找回来
and you ain't got fight enough to get her back!
打扰了吉姆先生  但
Um, excuse me, Mr. Jim, but...
-我试过让她来这里  -这算那种的让她来
-I tried to keep her here. -What kind of keeping is that?
耍了个诡计
Nothing but tricks!
如果你到了好莱坞
If you went to Hollywood
告诉琳达小姐多么的爱她
and told Miss Linda how much you loves her,
和多么的想她
and missed her, and told her that
以小姐爱听的口气跟她说
the way a lady likes to hear it told,
我跟你说她将会是
I'll betcha she'd be
最快凋谢的电影名星
the quickest ex-movie star that ever ex'd.
-你疯了妈咪  -我疯了吗
-You're crazy, Mamie. -I'm crazy?
我了解琳达小姐
I knows Miss Linda.
跟了解自己孩子般熟悉
I knows her like I knows my own kids.
她不是那种爱慕虚荣的美女
Why, she ain't the fancy type no more than you are.
她需要的是真正的你
What she wants is what you got right here.
但女人都需要听
But women has to
她们爱听的话
have them things told to them the right way.
你可将她们的心  像奶油般溶化
You could melt her heart right down to butter...
如果你用真心对待她们
if you'd only turn on the heat.
妈咪你会  你不会想要
Mamie, you don't, you don't
从他那里抢走别人的马子
try to take a fella's gal away from him..
当他送给他戒指后
.after he's bought the ring.
-或还是我的记忆是你吗  -还用你说
-Or, as I recall, do you? -Now you're talking!
当然  女人必需要慢慢的说
Sure! Women has to be told things the right way.
是的  先生
Yes, sir!
终于每晚
At last! The night I've been
我的梦就在这里
dreaming about, actually here.
这是我的婚礼  你让我成为个公主
This is my wedding. You make me feel like a kibitzer.
别误解我
Don't misunderstand me.
我快乐是因为这婚姻代表
I'm happy because this marriage means...
我们可以安定并免于担心
that we can all settle down and stop worrying.
希望我有的是你的信心  不是想法
I wish I had your confidence without your viewpoint.
我的双手合十  直到琳达和我
My fingers are crossed until Linda and I
搭上飞机直达约玛
are on that plane bound for Yuma.
-你在担心什么  -我也不清楚
-What's worrying you? -I don't know exact...
过去我也曾如此靠近婚礼
I've been this close to marriage before,
等醒来后发觉没有新娘  只是汉诺瓦一人
only to wake and find myself with no bride and a hangover.
女孩已经答应了  照片今晚洗出来
Look, the girl has said yes, the picture finishes tonight.
-进来  -一切都准备就绪
-Come in. -Everything is all set and ready.
会发生什么状况
What could possibly happen...
嗨  各位
Hi, fellas?
吉姆  你怎么会来这里
Jim! Wh...What brought you here?
火车  嘟嘟嘟  结婚吗  何时啊
Train. Chug-chug-chug-chug. Wedding? When is it?
-结婚  -是啊
-Wedding? -Yeah.
时间还没敲定呢
Uh, well, we hadn't set an exact time.
-你看到琳达吗  -没有  还没
-Have you seen Linda? -No. No, not yet.
我看到你的导演  他跟我说
Say, I saw your director. He told me
今晚最后一次拍摄呢
he was shooting the finale tonight.
因此我想看你如何拍照
Thought I'd like to see how you make pictures.
他不会
Uh, he wouldn't...
你不会喜欢今晚的过程
Y-You wouldn't like what they're doing tonight.
为什么
Why not?
很无聊的  科技的东西
That's dull, technical stuff.
我对科技这些
Well, I'm a dull,
本来就不太懂
technical sort of a fella.
也许你该等明天看琳达
Perhaps if you'd wait and see Linda tomorrow.
不
Oh, no!
我要看拍片的杀青
I want to see the finish.
你跟琳达对我很重要呢
The success of you and Linda means a lot to me, pal.
为何不自在点呢  你在说什么
Say, why don't you be yourself? What are you up to?
我是个混蛋
Well, I'm a son of a gun.
这是个美丽的欢迎方式
This is a beautiful hunk of welcome
一个人从东岸来到西岸
for a guy who comes coast to coast...
只想跟你说声圣诞快乐
just to wish you a Merry Christmas
还有婚礼的祝福
and a happy wedding.
复活节清晨当你来到酒店时
Remember how I suspected you
记得我有多么怀疑你
when you came to the Inn on Easter morning?
太蠢了不是吗
That was silly, wasn't it?
现在我知道他有目的
Now I know he's up to something.
等等  这样太不公平
Wait a minute. Let's not be unfair.
我们对待吉姆像个穷亲戚
We're treating Jim like a poor country cousin.
他没有任何恶意
He doesn't mean any harm.
-不  -不  他只想来看琳达
-No. -No. He just wants to see Linda.
让琳达跟他见面  男人不知在想什么
-Let's show him Linda! -Good will on earth toward men!
我们要去哪里  这是干嘛
Where are we going? What's this? Hey!
泰德  这是干什么
Hey, Ted, what is this?
我怕你会发疯的
I was afraid you'd gone crazy.
我会让他待在这里
I'll keep him here...
直到你跟琳达上了飞机
till you get Linda on that plane.
我最好把衣服穿好
I'd better get my clothes on.
我去看看他们准备的怎样
I'll go on the set and see how near ready they are.
我的衣服在这里啊
My clothes are in there!
-圣诞快乐  -吉姆兄弟
-Merry Christmas! -Jim! Pal!
等等  站住  我们在开玩笑啦
Wait! Stop! We were only fooling!
只有你才会这么想
Only you could think of a thing like that.
-你要打给谁  -不用管
-Who're you calling? -Nobody.
总机下班了
The operator's gone.
别紧张  别扭断你的脖子
Take it easy. Don't break you neck.
这是我们干过
It's one of the most authentic
最棒的一部片子
reproduction jobs we've ever done.
是吗
Is it?
这些摄影师的作品
All worked out from those photographs
在你康乃迪克那里拍摄的
we took of your place in Connecticut.
好  妈咪跟孩子们应该看到
Oh! Well, Mamie and the kids oughta see this.
他们绝不会相信的
They'd never believe it.
-有问题吗  -那棵圣诞树
-Anything wrong? -Well, that Christmas tree
摆在太外面了
is a little out of place.
我想没人会注意的  但我或者  琳达
I guess nobody'd notice that but me or... Linda.
我们要一起开始拍了
We're going to start rolling in a couple of minutes.
跟我来你就会看到一切了
Come along with me where you can see everything.
不  我待在幕后就好了
No. I'll just stay in the background.
我不懂你在说什么
I don't want to get in your way.
随你的意  一会见了
Suit yourself. I'll see you later.
好
Right.
好了  我们跟着你
All right, we're going to follow you
从酒店里面出来
on the boom from here inside the Inn.
当你到了那位置开始唱歌
When you get in the other set, do your song.
你的情绪应该很好
I think you have the mood.
你的好莱坞名声成空了
Your Hollywood success was empty.
你失去了爱你的人
You've lost the one man you love.
你知道  老故事了
You know, the usual hoke.
你娶了我会让我哭泣
Just make me cry and you can get to that wedding.
-准备彩排  -不  拜托  让它拍吧
-All ready for rehearsal! -No, please. Let's shoot it.
好的  开始吧
Okay. It's a take!
好了大家注意
All right, everybody,
舞台上安静  开始拍了
quiet on the stage. It's a take.
把它关掉
Close them up!
快点在这里安静点
Come on over there. Quiet down.
大家都准备好
Let's get settled, everybody.
快点  大家都准备好
Come on, everybody, let's get settled.
在拍电影呢
It's the picture.
带着扫把滚出去
Get out of here with your brooms.
雪打到你
Hit your snow!
好了  开始拍
All right, roll them!
抱歉  当红灯亮起时
Sorry, but when the red light's on,
就算摄影蓬是你的也不能进来
you couldn't get in even if you owned the studio.
但  包伯  重要事情
But, Pop, this is important.
我知道  灯也是呢
I know. So is the light.
动作还原  音乐
Hit your playback! Music!
好了  开始
All right, action!
跟我过去熟悉的一样
Just like the ones I used to know
树梢发出了光茫
Where the treetops glisten
孩子在聆听
And children listen
听着雪地里的圣诞铃声
To hear sleigh bells in the snow
梦想着白色的
Dreaming of a white
圣诞节
Christmas
我写下每张圣诞卡片
With every Christmas card I write
祝你的日子都快乐
May your days be merry
与光明
And bright
-吉姆  -切掉  切掉
-Jim! -Cut it! Cut it!
很好
That's it!
好了  各位
All right, gentlemen.
他的五分钟怎么这么远呢
How could he get that far in five minutes?
女孩子一定愿意
The lady must've been willing.
但世界不给我们机会
But the world can't do this to us.
她来了  从街上过来
Here she comes down the street
我承认我的失败
I'll admit my defeat
我已经赢得芳心
I've won my hot toddy
在我怕的身体
Over my scarred body
我知道我赢了
I knew that I'd win
唱着
Singing
但等到她跟你跳舞时
But wait until she gets a load of your dancing
我们在酒店里唱着
We'll stay at the Inn singing
只有我一人  我必需练习跳舞
All by myself I'll have to stick to my dancing
不我的朋友  我来这里
Oh, no, my friend I'm here to end
解决你跳舞困扰与争扎
Your dancing trouble and strife
这会很有趣的
Oh, this will be fun.
打代跑小姐回到我的人生
Miss Hit-And-Run has come back into my life
-我们待在酒店  -我们重新开始
-We'll stay at the Inn -We'll have to begin
-唱歌  -跳舞
-Singing -Dancing
我们彼此配合
We've each other to cling to
你会懂得如何唱歌
-You'll be easy to sing to -And you're
你会懂得如何跳舞
Easy to dance with
让过去时光逝去
So let the old year die
跟它说声再见
With a fond good-bye
我们的希望跟风筝一样高
And our hopes as high as a kite
我们的爱不会再有波折
How can our love go wrong, dear
从新的一年开始渡过
If we start the New Year right